<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Essays | Hellender]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.hellender.com/blog/categories/essays/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.hellender.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-07T15:26:17-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.hellender.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hellender]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do Dead Dolphins Still Smile?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.hellender.com/blog/2015/01/12/do-dead-dolphins-still-smile/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-12T00:13:40-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.hellender.com/blog/2015/01/12/do-dead-dolphins-still-smile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Error processing input, expected syntax: {% soundcloud type id [options...] %} received: <a href="https://soundcloud.com/hellender/do-dead-dolphins-still-smile">https://soundcloud.com/hellender/do-dead-dolphins-still-smile</a> </p>

<p>A speech from a few years ago, when I was still doing very poorly from PTSD. This was a response to my being slut-shamed by my community and family of origin. After years of abuse, I had lots of questions and did some research to find what answers I could. This is some of what I found out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[And Then There Was Plan B]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.hellender.com/blog/2015/01/05/and-then-there-was-plan-b/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-05T16:12:41-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.hellender.com/blog/2015/01/05/and-then-there-was-plan-b</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I took Plan B. Plan A turned into Plan Accident. Because there was another contraceptive option available to me today, I had the freedom to choose.</p>

<p>The comdom failed. Seven years with the same partner and that many without an accident as well didn&rsquo;t mean we were ready. Court drama is stressful for me; I think a fetus would be affected. I am not planning on having children at this time, and use prophylactics to exercise my right to choose.</p>

<p>When I first discovered the broken barrier I tried a few things to prevent pregnancy. I washed, deeply. I asked my partner to help insert coffee into my body. He blew it in with a straw as I sat on the sink hooting about aneurysms. I dug about up there, searching for any tactile evidence of semen. I tasted the fluids. I inserted cranberries. All of these actions except one were actually taken. Historically, women inserted stones prior to sex in order to prevent pregnancy. The broken condom had me wishing I&rsquo;d resorted to similar methods prior to copulation. Of course we live in modern times, and I had the advantage of more options than stones or wire hangers. But not all do.</p>

<p>I remember a friend who at thirteen became sexually active and—uneducated and unsupported—feared disclosing this to her mom. Knowing the mom, I knew her reasons. My friend desperately wanted to confide about her experiences; she wrote an autobiography framed in the context of her sexual activity, in Sharpie, on the inside of a coat of hers.</p>

<p>One day, she pulled her bass amp apart, revealing a used pregnancy test and paraphernalia. My friend sensed that in her home it was unsafe to discard a test—a test that gave her the knowledge that she was not pregnant.</p>

<p>It was difficult, but not illegal for my friend to have the test, save for in her own home. There, she didn&rsquo;t feel trust and understanding, and was ashamed of her development. She closed the back of her amp up, with the test and the other incriminating evidence inside. My friend was guilty—guilty of growing up. She was guilty of being a sexual creature, and for desiring knowledge.</p>

<p>When I obtained the Plan B, I enjoyed the legal protection to do so without a prescription because I&rsquo;m over fifteen. This recent progress saved me the time and effort of going to a clinic. As a survivor of child sexual abuse, taking charge of my reproductive health is a challenge. The ease of availability of Plan B ensured that I benefited from a dose of maximum efficacy. Plan B, like Plan Accident, can fail, but I got the best shot I could at it working due to new laws protecting my rights to do such. My friend can now enjoy her expanded reproductive rights as an adult. To my knowledge, she has no unwanted children. However, she was not the only sexually active child in history. The girls of today are given access to condoms and birth control pills, so why not Plan B? It would help prevent any children from trying to replicate the hormone dose with normal birth control pills.</p>

<p>Imagine if my friend, or a girl like her, could&rsquo;ve purchased Plan B and taken it the day after her unprotected sexual encounter. Sure, she didn&rsquo;t conceive that time, but days went by, possibly weeks even, where she must&rsquo;ve privately fretted about her status. This stress might&rsquo;ve distracted her from her studies, and could&rsquo;ve been largely reduced by the use of Plan B. In her story she didn&rsquo;t conceive, but in other stories conception does occur and Plan B can help a child avoid the strain of gestation and a possible abortion later on. Plan B is an option that reduces the amount of difficult choices a female may have to face, freeing her to focus more on other things.</p>

<p>With the new law, my friend&rsquo;s mom could buy her the Plan B pill today, but this wouldn&rsquo;t have been a viable option, as my friend had a poor relationship with her mom, and couldn&rsquo;t trust that she wouldn&rsquo;t be disciplined for seeking her help. By granting children of any age access to Plan B, we could help elevate the status of females. Freedom of choice should apply as soon as the choice could be faced, rather than at an arbitrary age.</p>

<p>As a teen child, I was raped frequently. Had I forgotten to take my birth control pill, and a condom failed, I might&rsquo;ve risked pregnancy by a teacher. Had that occurred, I sure would&rsquo;ve wanted to continue with my choice not to conceive and access to an alternative. Plan B becoming available to girls may represent one change in how powerless child sex abuse victims are to control their experience. I know precious few things seem in control to a child sexual abuse victim. Their knowing they can legally access emergency contraception might also help them deduce that it&rsquo;s okay to discuss matters of reproductive and sexual health, including abuse.</p>

<p>Besides some nervous shakes, I&rsquo;ve had no side effects. I&rsquo;ve sat by the fire, grateful for my rights for hours now. I&rsquo;m hopeful that we can work to grant those most vulnerable the right to access emergency contraception as well.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s another thing going on with my body, I&rsquo;m crying. This may be a side effect of the dose of hormones, but for some reason I don&rsquo;t think so.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Prisoners' Birthdays]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.hellender.com/blog/2014/08/10/the-prisoners-birthdays/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-10T14:08:34-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.hellender.com/blog/2014/08/10/the-prisoners-birthdays</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Error processing input, expected syntax: {% soundcloud type id [options...] %} received: <a href="https://soundcloud.com/hellender/cowboy-journalist">https://soundcloud.com/hellender/cowboy-journalist</a> </p>

<p><a href="/images/Petulance-Prisoners-Birthdays.png"><img class="no-border" src="/images/Petulance-Prisoners-Birthdays-small.png" title="Petulance the cupcake, in The Prisoners' Birthdays" ></a></p>

<p>Ill again from the vigilance, my mind is roiling. On the loft bed above me, Elliott sleeps. I&rsquo;m concerned with two men. I know where they are too; one is in prison in Louisiana, and the other in jail in Texas. Both will soon have a birthday behind bars.</p>

<p>Some have suggested that pills might help these obsessions. What they don&rsquo;t know is I negate the need for my own lobotomy by thinking about these things. From the back to the front, and back again, boom boom boom. These circuits soar over the neuronal quagmires, keep me just rattled enough to stave off sleep and the dreams. This way is best, yes. To be disturbed by external situations rather than internal is more moral I think.</p>

<p>From the slums of my skull come the comparisons. The plea deals, the relative length of incarceration (both being jailed for less than two years now). Both bearing Irish-American surnames, the birthday inmates have inherited an honest history of hardship. Both have the sad eyes of experience. Neither of them are past fifty, and both enjoy to smoke. I&rsquo;m looking for a cigarette right now, it&rsquo;s all so true.</p>

<p>Just like the inevitability of death, I like to think about this this because it can be counted on that today, both will be lining up for food, like schoolchildren. Both will be surrounded by people not of their choosing, and I know this will be the same way on their birthdays. It&rsquo;s not my fault. Yet, I&rsquo;m uncomfortable on their behalf. Some would call it Satan, others PTSD; but what I&rsquo;ve got is a borderline case of the blues. So do they, I figure. There&rsquo;s not too much to be happy about for them these days.  Except the possibility of freedom, the hope. Well, I&rsquo;ll be damned, the hope is a wonderful thing. Here&rsquo;s where the contrasts start dancing for me. I tip my head in thanks. It&rsquo;s not every day that my mind lets me in on my thoughts. Some would call it God, others disassociation; but what I&rsquo;ve got is a borderline case of the brains.</p>

<p>The prisoner in Louisiana is going to be off the block in a year and a half. Being a sex offender, former art teacher Samuel McCarty will have to register and go through probation for years to come, yet he will be outside. I&rsquo;m sure the structure of his sentence offers some degree of opportunity. He did try to get parole, even though that&rsquo;s not allowed in the terms of his plea deal. He almost got it too, with an error having been in the system. I know this because I helped catch it when he was up for parole after a year, two years before I expected him to be eligible for such. Knowing the structure of the sentence had been helping me sleep, but this opportunity was not to be missed by the convicted molester, and he had enough hope to try. Prison hasn&rsquo;t dampened Samuel McCarty&rsquo;s spirit much, I figure. He will need it, because a child molester who built his career on education will have to be pretty adventurous to make ends meet. As of six months ago, McCarty was apparantly ready for the challenge. I was not, and neither was the system, they think he should be behind bars for a year and a half longer. Spending less time in prison than the system took to put him there, less time there than he did committing his crimes, he will face his second interred birthday out of three soon, and he knows it.</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t decide how much light I want to let in. I open the curtain, I close it. Good thing the boy&rsquo;s up top, down here&rsquo;s like slow strobe. That lighthouse. That beacon. Those borderline brains I&rsquo;ve got are using introverted intuition, but never mind the pop psychology if it&rsquo;s nothing to ya. Don&rsquo;t scry for me, I&rsquo;ve got all the flash I can handle in this pan.</p>

<p>They don&rsquo;t do candles in cells, huh? No, probably not. Does a prisoner get an extra helping of beaver tail when it&rsquo;s their birthday? Do they give their prison birthday buddies stamps and sharps? Maybe, but, no probably not. I&rsquo;d like to think they get a discount on commissary, at least. I&rsquo;m probably a little low on blood sugar. Is Elliott asleep or just dead? I can&rsquo;t tell, he&rsquo;s got absolutely no signs of life from where I&rsquo;m sitting, but then again, I&rsquo;m under him. My cat sits under my chair, I wonder if she thinks I&rsquo;m dead. Oh wait, I&rsquo;m not asleep. I forgot that, better get back to the wowzer thoughts or else I&rsquo;ll be&hellip; dead? I&rsquo;d told Elliott that the beatnik era of our lives was coming to a close recently. I&rsquo;m 27. I just don&rsquo;t believe in superstition anymore, so if I want the era to end with death, I&rsquo;ll most likely have to be somehow complicit. I always was late to bloom, in some ways. I just want that cigarette.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d bet the prisoner in Texas would like a smoke too. Being publicly associated with Anonymous as he is, former journalist Barrett Brown is known to have a struggle with addiction, and not just ciggies, either. This smack-addled satirist initially faced 105 years in prison for posting a link to beaucoup documents from intelligence corporations, some of which were damning. He also unintentionally exposed the credit card data of many people involved in the surveillance industry. When the feds gave him and his mother a hard time down there in Texas, he went off of his meds and into a state. He giggled, he ranted, he threatened. He called it &ldquo;Revenge of the Lithe&rdquo;. Later that day, a counterstrike from the feds left him battered and booked. Boom boom boom. They had trouble figuring out exactly what a link was, and what laws were broken, but eventually his charges were reduced, he signed the plea deal, and now awaits court. Recently, it got pushed back until after his birthday. He has already served nearly two years on trumped up charges without any knowledge of how much longer he has to go. With enemies in Anonymous, Los Zetas and the U.S. government, this mind in a cage will surely have much else to negotiate besides revolt now.</p>

<p>It would seem that the government finds a mind a terrible thing, and the rape of my minor person despicable enough to correct for almost as long as a case of borderline brains. With his birthday, the molester will have the reward of knowing it&rsquo;s the second to last one like this. He has a better shot at stability, and that&rsquo;s good seeing as how he&rsquo;ll be out in the community I&rsquo;m from within two years. As for that muckraking journalist, he will have to wait. For now, I&rsquo;m sure he knows that he will have the birthday blessing of vigilance. He gets blessed every day, it would seem from his writings. It&rsquo;s like a self imposed structure, I figure. A body needs some things known. Barrett Brown&rsquo;s brain keeps the schedule of a knight as he faces his birthday behind bars, and for its suffering it will possibly be enhanced as one of the more morally engaged minds in our country, if it doesn&rsquo;t go utterly mad. For now, Brown&rsquo;s out of solitary, and so the butterfly&rsquo;s off the wheel for his birthday, still alive to tell just who put him there.</p>

<p>Elliott quietly taps away now, here down on my level. He&rsquo;s definitely alive. A few basic tasks, and he&rsquo;s off into the nether reaches of extroverted intuition, so curious. He knows all about this by now, including my knowing this well enough now to type it out. He understands, he reads, he writes. I&rsquo;m stymied. Must be the blood sugar. Or knowing that I&rsquo;m known, or not knowing. Or just something, Satan or what have you it&rsquo;s always got to be something for this witch. I never was baptized. I&rsquo;ve read that many incarcerated people are believers. I know these two men on my mind are not. I&rsquo;d like to wish happy birthday, to the molester and the muckraker both imprisoned in our system. Now, if only more would wake up. Until then, God have mercy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
