<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Short Stories | Hellender]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.hellender.com/blog/categories/short-stories/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.hellender.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-10T19:31:21-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.hellender.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hellender]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bounding Hare]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.hellender.com/blog/2014/06/18/bounding-hare/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-18T05:33:59-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.hellender.com/blog/2014/06/18/bounding-hare</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Error processing input, expected syntax: {% soundcloud type id [options...] %} received: <a href="https://soundcloud.com/hellender/bounding-hare-score">https://soundcloud.com/hellender/bounding-hare-score</a> </p>

<p><img class="no-border left" src="/images/JumpingRabbit2.png" title="Crossing &ldquo;A young cottontail bounds through the grass, on a rendezvous with fate&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>The cultivated blades sheltered me as I began my last dance. My partner watched across the way. I skipped into a collision, ricocheted and collapsed. There, I lay on my side, crushed. I was leaving myself for dead.</p>

<p>Every breath hurt more. I was messing myself from the pain. The bleary sky lights overtook my upward eye, or was it already gone? I felt my face pulling in on itself. A dark shape came to take me for life.</p>

<p>I looked hard, I tried not to move, but my legs kept flailing. It was onto me. I knew it saw my body, so I gave up. I forgot what my mother taught me about staying so still, and I looked back and forth at it. It wasn&rsquo;t my partner, but I loved it as if I had found her in that scary shape. It took me.</p>

<p>In it&rsquo;s clutches, I went up. I saw all black. It placed me in between its breasts? I was not in its mouth! Why? I kicked off to escape. I forgot about all the pain, but I still couldn&rsquo;t escape! Powerful gravity had my limbs stuck. Like a nightmare, but not being chased and eaten, A terror! A TERROR!</p>

<p>It had roared at me as I lay on softness with jagged ice beneath. The round light above was not what it used to be to me, I had never looked at it this way before. It was surrounded by the entrance of my home. The shape approached and jarred me. I couldn&rsquo;t see the light anymore. Another shape came up and growled. I lost consciousness.</p>

<p>I thought my field was on fire. I could smell the itchy smoke, I could feel myself throb with a cough. Wondering where my partner was wouldn&rsquo;t stop the pain from growing with the flames. I wondered, did Onawa feel this too? I knew somehow she didn&rsquo;t right then. The fire smell was so close to me, no doubt she&rsquo;d be dead already, so, no she hadn&rsquo;t been feeling that screaming burn any longer, I figured. I was happy for her, and then I sneezed. Every bone in my face had become two or more, and they all shifted and pinched the miserable meat between. Oooooooooooow, I whispered.</p>

<p>The world was spinning around me. Or was I spinning? Either way, I was on tilt.</p>

<p>Oh, now I get it, I remember thinking. I&rsquo;m dead and nobody told me. How silly of me.</p>

<p>I was born again by the river, like before, but in a big cube. Why was I wet? I didn&rsquo;t know.</p>

<p>The fire seemed to be over. The wind tortured my new body. Bound from within, I couldn&rsquo;t move my young limbs to see if she had been spared. Every follicle on my exposed body dug like claws into me when the dusty wind rustled my hair. Why did the wind sound like bees? I braced for the stings. They never came. I tried to soothe myself by cracking my back, but it was already done. Birds and bees were in the whirling devil around me. I blinked my one eye, having never teared at pain before. My love for my partner welled and drowned me, knowing I&rsquo;d never see her again. It was a cold reality. So cold I was shivering. I considered this. I thought that the new body was numb, but I was really on ice the whole time? Why wouldn&rsquo;t it just devour me, why did I feel so much pain?</p>

<p>As my first nightmares progressed, I went to what they call hell. Fleeing the fire, I was on a trail bound for the woods. As I climbed up into the forest, it became night. For the first time, I saw trees, not from underneath, but from the side. Like the shapes who took me, they were dark silhouettes, gnarled things, and they wanted back the bark I&rsquo;d chewed. They were horrifying. I tried to run faster than the wind, tried to be the wind, but I still saw the trees skin, their hands reaching for me. I had a hard time not dying of fright from the skin hands. They bowed and reached for me, gracing my ears. So these were hands, I thought.</p>

<p>Winds rushed through the trees as they collected me. Whispering and screeching, they enclosed me and discussed my fate. I didn&rsquo;t want to know their language, but now that I do, I can&rsquo;t forget it. It was very cold.</p>

<p>They talked about my body and what they would do to it.</p>

<p>When I awoke, I was being hunted by the beast shapes again. I realized they sounded just like the skin trees. They approached, and they whispered and wailed all night by what looked to be the remaining fire. How terrible were these tree beasts, that with their skin, they don&rsquo;t kindle. They must be the source of the fire, I realized. They were going to cook me.</p>

<p>My cube had soft things for me to lay in. The pain throbbed my whole body. I was so still. If only my mother could see me now. If only I could scratch my ears.</p>

<p>I was moved by the beast. As it lifted me, my down eye peeled off of the softness. Cold water was running over my face. I tried to blink, but I don&rsquo;t think that&rsquo;s what happened. Just like when kicking off, I was infantile in my execution.</p>

<p>Screaming wasn&rsquo;t an option when they put me back down on my bad side. If I was to escape, I&rsquo;d need them to think I was dead, so I had to stay so quiet.</p>

<p>What was that? That thing? I didn&rsquo;t want that. I heard them say &ldquo;broccoli&rdquo; when they put it in my personal space. It was like the trees didn&rsquo;t even know how to eat me.</p>

<p>They were warm, and smelled of their fleshy meals. I knew they had been eating meat, the &ldquo;broccoli&rdquo; smelled like the field goliaths. Were these even trees? No, I remember realizing, they&rsquo;re people. My Mother always taught me to stay far away from people, because they were supposed to be the deadliest hunters. But these weren&rsquo;t very lethal, they were stupid for sure. Maybe that really is what people are though, I realized, having never encountered them before. My partner would get breakfast by the people&rsquo;s homes, but I knew to stay where it smelled green. These people smell green.</p>

<p>Why couldn&rsquo;t I just go home? Someone else would take it soon. This broccoli was so big, how would I chew it? My mouth won&rsquo;t move, I tried to lick a pest off of my nose, but no. It just kept biting. I needed to suckle. I&rsquo;d been born again to people. People tree beasts, smell like green, and not too bright.</p>

<p>Somehow, I knew she wasn&rsquo;t going to be saved by rebirth. It had to do with the people beasts that I was reborn. I began to envy her for what must’ve been a swift demise. If they&rsquo;re this bad at killing me, what else will they try? Had they already killed all the others with their firepower? If so, why did I smell trees still? This was a confusing time. The night sky light told me that I&rsquo;d be this way for a long time. I was shocked that I was going to be at all. Would I feel more and more pain? I licked my paw to keep from screaming. It turned out to be true that I&rsquo;d never see her again. She was lost to that itchy smoke, that smoke that was ebbing in and out of my nares.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d never faced grief in my past life. As a kit, I was a little much for my mother. My two sisters and brother called me Pipsqueak, being the runt and all. They wished they hadn&rsquo;t when by the second week I was as fat as a young buck. That&rsquo;s part of why I was out of the nest so early. Foraging was hard. I scooted about for hours to the first aromatic thing, savored the juices and fibers, and found the next. Life got sweeter with each precious, tender shoot. Some of the best treats were hard-won in the woods across the way from where I stayed. I&rsquo;d learned to cross, even though I felt exposed.</p>

<p>I met Onawa in those woods. She was older, wiser, and had a big soft belly I loved. I remember dancing for her. She was not very impressed.</p>

<p>In time, she came to love me, though. I&rsquo;d see her, and greet her with a good ruffing all the time, until one day she let me mount her. That&rsquo;s when we became partners. I&rsquo;ll never forget her, or the way she let me have her droppings before I went home. Ah, life.</p>

<p>All these things hit me in waves of profound knowledge. I was the wisest I&rsquo;d ever been, yet my thoughts kept racing. My head hurt. I flopped myself into a better spot and tried to focus on the misty afternoons in my mind. I felt warm there underneath the soft things. The visions got duller as the pain got sharper.</p>

<p>It was ICE! Icy ice all around me! I craned to escape. I couldn&rsquo;t. This was no way to die!</p>

<p>In the green cube, I couldn’t move my back legs to scratch the stings I could feel. A tick had claimed my earlobe, a fly spat on my eye, and a large dungbeetle lumbered over. When I got a good look at him, I chatted him, asking that he please move out of my personal space. He stuck his butt in the air. It was rude.</p>

<p>I could smell the earth again. The night had moistened things. We were by a river, I realized. I could smell the fishbones nearby. Ants sampled my body, but mercifully only from the numb parts. Decompositions surrounded me.</p>

<p>I was lying with my collapsed eye upward. I had little experience looking through one of those, but such is par for course when in a new body. There was only a little field of vision left, and what I saw were bats. Many bats spun around my head into the night, picking off of the fruit and broccoli left for me.  I’m not sure the bats ever stopped.</p>

<p>Everybody was entitled to what was left of me. This didn’t exclude me necessarily, but the nature of my challenges were that I couldn’t take full advantage. Weak but live, I figured this must be how the beasts want me when they eat. Would I ever be able to fight the fleas again? They really bothered me.</p>

<p>Morning came, and so did soup. It was in a long, hard thing, maybe a bug part? It pumped my mouth full of the strangest food I’d ever tasted, over and over. I ate up gratefully. Since I&rsquo;d started eating bark, I started to like it all. This soup tasted like the willow bark in back of the cultivated grass. The meal went on and on. Now this really was much better than bark, I tell you! The fleas agreed; their mornings were sweetened as well.</p>

<p>I smelled no smoke that morning, no evidence of fire. My eyes revealed to me the lush greens and golds I knew before. I couldn’t see much, but I knew that the fire never happened. Bolting to find Onawa would be great, but I was stuck in the clutches of the beasts.</p>

<p>One of the beasts was a canine. I felt it scratch at the ground, I heard it whimper. The bigger people beasts wouldn’t let it have me yet. Oh, how long?</p>

<p>Inside of my cube, my new body shifted and spun. The vibrations made my bones tickle. The tree beasts had us in a firebird, flying across the desert to another land, to their nest? The beasts brought the canine too.</p>

<p>Many beasts I couldn’t smell spoke and chanted on that ride. My dizzy cube kept speaking to me in muttered music. The breasted beast kept coming in to feed me, not unlike my mother when I was a kit. What exactly they were talking about on that ride, I’m unsure of, but I know it was spring for them too, by the way the did it. The two people beasts were mates. The canine was their kit. Did they know I was now like a kit too? Was it my smell that had them nurturing me?</p>

<p>The vibrations stopped, they weren’t around, the people beasts. The canine sniffed hungrily at my cube. I had no problem being so still.</p>

<p>When I first arrived in the form I am now, I smelled a feline. I felt reassured, thinking that would surely be the canine’s demise. Felines are so much bigger than canines.</p>

<p>The breasted beast continued to fail at eating me. It would come around to give me more of that soup from the bug, the best soup I’d ever had. I noticed that when I was hungry, I hurt so badly. I tried chatting it many times to tell it how much I loved the soup, that I only wanted more and more, but it didn’t matter. It’d give me soup, I’d feel better, then after a while the bats and birds circling over my head returned. For days I’d linger in that form.</p>

<p>I was on the soup when the beast almost drowned me. Nimbly, I kicked in the water. It held my rear end down, so I soiled the water. Survival isn’t always becoming of a gentlebuck.</p>

<p>It wrapped me in softness and fed me more amazing soup. This time, the numbness only hit my body.  I thought of Onawa. If there was no fire, and the tree people were invasive but stupid, then she might still be in her field. She might be about to have my kits, I thought. The beast bound my body. The bondage pulled my fur and stiffened my hips. It hurt.</p>

<p>The last straw before I escaped was a good one.  They’d been giving me exotic hay, and hey, I wasn’t about to leave that behind. Numbness was fun.</p>

<p>I wriggled my front end up to the border of my form. Even bound, my back end worked better on the soup. I put my front legs on the edge and pulled with all my might. With one extra belly crunch, I was halfway out.</p>

<p>I spazzed hard, and rolled out onto a soft surface. It bounced. Was all the land like this between me and Onawa, I wondered? I’d never been in this kind of desert, it was warm and springy. I could do this, I remember thinking.</p>

<p>I moved swiftly to cover those few inches I did. Soft obstacles, like little mountains blocked me from simply heading North. Forging a new trail on this land was hard, but the land wasn’t. I would get going, then roll down the tall softness, to bounce right back were I started.</p>

<p>I had rolled to the edge of the land. My head was off a cliff, my body still grounded. This was badlands.</p>

<p>The feline stalked my hind in the softness. I writhed to get some purchase, but I began to fall off of the cliff. The feline struck me, pinning me between the soft cliff and it’s claws. It picked me up by the bondage, and took me outside, to examine me under the sky lights.</p>

<p>Felines were smaller than I’d thought, but still I felt tiny in it’s jaws. My good eye watched the grass fly by beneath me. I couldn’t see above, but I knew the bats were back.</p>

<p>It was another impact!</p>

<p>The feline yowled and ran off. The person beast didn’t strike my shaking body, though. It gently collected me in softness. It really didn’t intend to eat me, I realized.</p>

<p>The beast placed me in the form. It talked to me. I listened. It knew my name.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Ooodin&hellip; I love you, Odin. Please rest up now.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I chatted it back, I felt the love. We fell asleep like this, and the feline stayed away.</p>

<p>When my mother was killed, I didn’t understand. Nobody was there to save her from the feline attacking our nest. I didn’t understand why I was born again to this beast. Had she lived, could my mother have saved me from all this change?</p>

<p>Onawa would have to raise our family without me. I couldn’t save her from uncertainty. Not before, not now. My beast approaches.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Odin, are you hungry, Bunny Boy?&rdquo;</p>

<p>My eyes blink now. I can see the hay and berries with both of them. Only time will tell when, and if, I may be unbound. I’d love to dance again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
