<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Hellender</title><link href="http://www.hellender.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.hellender.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.hellender.com/</id><updated>2017-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Are the Peacemakers Blessed?</title><link href="http://www.hellender.com/blog/are-the-peacemakers-blessed" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hellender</name></author><id>tag:www.hellender.com,2017-06-15:/blog/are-the-peacemakers-blessed</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This essay was originally posted to the (now defunct) &lt;em&gt;Liberal Herald&lt;/em&gt; in early 2015. The 100-year anniversary of the Espionage act inspired me to republish it, and reboot this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Charles Schenck, Chelsea Manning and Edward Snowden bear the weight of the world and burdensome policy." src="/images/LH1.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Charles Schenck, Chelsea Manning and Edward Snowden bear the weight of the world and burdensome policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convoluted ethical reasoning has …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This essay was originally posted to the (now defunct) &lt;em&gt;Liberal Herald&lt;/em&gt; in early 2015. The 100-year anniversary of the Espionage act inspired me to republish it, and reboot this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Charles Schenck, Chelsea Manning and Edward Snowden bear the weight of the world and burdensome policy." src="/images/LH1.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Charles Schenck, Chelsea Manning and Edward Snowden bear the weight of the world and burdensome policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convoluted ethical reasoning has buttressed the Espionage Act for nearly a century. In 1919, Charles Schenck, General Secretary on the Executive Committee of the Socialist Party in Pennsylvania, was convicted along with Elizabeth Baer for violating the Espionage Act of 1917, although the intelligence he gathered and distributed along with Bear was open source. During WWI, Schenck had distributed more than 15,000 leaflets to men urging them to avoid the draft, citing the Thirteenth Amendment’s prohibition of involuntary servitude as a rationale. Schenck and Baer appealed their convictions, arguing that the Espionage Act of 1917 would negatively impact free discussion of the war, a right protected by the First Amendment of the U.S. Constitution. When the Espionage Act was put into question by the Schenck and Baer appeals, the Court ruled that the Espionage Act was constitutional. Today the original Espionage Act of 1917 has been amended several times. Some have called for a repeal. I suggest that we consider how the Espionage Act has come into play in current times to weigh its value for the U.S. moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former NSA contractor Edward Snowden revealed details of secret surveillance and security vulnerabilities permitted by the U.S. government. Many are aware that he has been granted political asylum in Russia and won’t return to the U.S. for now. He is reported to have claimed that he wouldn't get a fair trial if he did. This statement is supported by the fact that the Espionage Act prohibits the release of confidential state information, and allows for no ethical arguments. Even though Snowden divulged that the American public and foreign entities who traffic into U.S. territory were being illegally spied on, he legally has no defense under the Espionage Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snowden was exposed to secrets as part of his contract, and responded with dissenting action based on moral logic. He didn’t seek out secrets, they were part of his work environment, and yet because he knew them and leaked so much information, he is officially non grata to the U.S. President Obama has echoed this sentiment in his appraisal of Snowden’s actions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I will say that our nation's defense depends in part on the fidelity of those entrusted with our nation's secrets. (...) Moreover, the sensational way in which these disclosures have come out has often shed more heat than light, while revealing methods to our adversaries that could impact our operations in ways that we may not fully understand for years to come.&amp;quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it possible that these operations had not been fully understood by those undertaking them for years? The government has been enabled by the Espionage Act and the limited rights of whistleblowers. Now the U.S. President warns that due to leaks of true information, the NSA might fail to grasp how to properly respond to these revelations for years to come. This harkens back to the Schenck case, wherein his moral argument, based on the First Amendment, was invalidated by Judge Oliver Wendell Holmes, who declared:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“The most stringent protection of free speech would not protect a man in falsely shouting fire in a theatre and causing a panic. (...)The question in every case is whether the words used are used in such circumstances and are of such a nature as to create a clear and present danger that they will bring about the substantive evils that Congress has a right to prevent.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shooting the messenger is a well known tactic for those looking to avoid the propagation of truth. This metaphor can be extended and applied to the well-known real life case of Chelsea Manning. After leaking an unparalleled amount of information, she was tried under the Espionage Act and dishonorably discharged from military duties. She had discovered information such as the as the Iraqi and Afghan War Logs, along with many other documents, and was intent on sharing them. Among the offences she was charged with was a violation of the Espionage Act. She suffered greatly for the decision to express dissent through information, not unlike like the earlier victims of the Espionage Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though she was a soldier, Manning’s will for peace overrode her loyalty to a system she was discovering to be broken. Her First Amendment Rights didn’t apply as a whistleblower, and she signed a plea agreement. In the 1919 trial against Charles Schenck, Judge Holmes believed that expressions that posed a “clear and present danger” and had a good chance of success should be punished, but drew the line at punishing ideas. However, the effect of his rulings helped set a standard that allows the possibility of punishing a person for sharing or acting upon an ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="George Bellows &amp;quot;Blessed are the Peacemakers&amp;quot;" src="/images/Blessed_are_the_Peacemakers.gif" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;A satirical cartoon featuring Jesus as a prisoner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a depiction by George Bellows of Jesus, the quintessential idealist, in prison, it is written that “Thou shalt not kill” and “Blessed are the peacemakers”. Noble are the peacemakers, sure, but are they actually blessed by those in the position to do so? President Obama hasn't protected Manning, but he has blessed her out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“If I was to release stuff, information that I’m not authorized to release, I’m breaking the law. (...) We’re a nation of laws. We don’t individually make our own decisions about how the laws operate. (…) He broke the law.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any action that breaks the law is considered a crime. Considering what is and isn’t offensive is a nuanced ethical process. It’s difficult to reach a consensus on what constitutes crime, but it’s notable that the majority opinion of the community is a factor in determining standards of criminal behavior. It’s time to assert our  will through discussions of the cases being tried under violations of the U.S. Espionage Act for the sake of future change. I think that through the might of increased public awareness, we can help Congress make moves towards reforming the Espionage Act to better serve the people, rather than three letter agencies. It is currently possible for the Supreme Court Justices to revisit the constitutionality of the Espionage Act, in the case of an appeal. With the threat of heavy sentences often being held over defendants, plea deals that include forfeiting most rights to appeal are normal and thus this situation rarely occurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being American means opportunity and reward for so many. Political prisoners often receive no compensation or reward other than that of public support (in some cases). Often, they are brave people with something to lose by taking a stand. Shouldn’t the Supreme Court Justices bless the peacemakers by extending whistleblower protection to include ethical defense rights in Espionage Act cases? I say they should, lest the peacemakers continue to be damned.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Essays"></category></entry><entry><title>Bounding Hare</title><link href="http://www.hellender.com/blog/bounding-hare" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hellender</name></author><id>tag:www.hellender.com,2017-06-15:/blog/bounding-hare</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on a previous iteration of this blog on Wed, June 18, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bounding Hare" src="/images/JumpingRabbit2.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cultivated blades sheltered me as I began my last dance. My partner watched across the way. I skipped into a collision, ricocheted and collapsed. There, I lay on my side, crushed. I was leaving myself …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on a previous iteration of this blog on Wed, June 18, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bounding Hare" src="/images/JumpingRabbit2.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cultivated blades sheltered me as I began my last dance. My partner watched across the way. I skipped into a collision, ricocheted and collapsed. There, I lay on my side, crushed. I was leaving myself for dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every breath hurt more. I was messing myself from the pain. The bleary sky lights overtook my upward eye, or was it already gone? I felt my face pulling in on itself. A dark shape came to take me for life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked hard, I tried not to move, but my legs kept flailing. It was onto me. I knew it saw my body, so I gave up. I forgot what my mother taught me about staying so still, and I looked back and forth at it. It wasn't my partner, but I loved it as if I had found her in that scary shape. It took me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In it's clutches, I went up. I saw all black. It placed me in between its breasts? I was not in its mouth! Why? I kicked off to escape. I forgot about all the pain, but I still couldn't escape! Powerful gravity had my limbs stuck. Like a nightmare, but not being chased and eaten, A terror! A TERROR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had roared at me as I lay on softness with jagged ice beneath. The round light above was not what it used to be to me, I had never looked at it this way before. It was surrounded by the entrance of my home. The shape approached and jarred me. I couldn't see the light anymore. Another shape came up and growled. I lost consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought my field was on fire. I could smell the itchy smoke, I could feel myself throb with a cough. Wondering where my partner was wouldn't stop the pain from growing with the flames. I wondered, did Onawa feel this too? I knew somehow she didn't right then. The fire smell was so close to me, no doubt she'd be dead already, so, no she hadn't been feeling that screaming burn any longer, I figured. I was happy for her, and then I sneezed. Every bone in my face had become two or more, and they all shifted and pinched the miserable meat between. Oooooooooooow, I whispered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world was spinning around me. Or was I spinning? Either way, I was on tilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, now I get it, I remember thinking. I'm dead and nobody told me. How silly of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was born again by the river, like before, but in a big cube. Why was I wet? I didn't know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fire seemed to be over. The wind tortured my new body. Bound from within, I couldn't move my young limbs to see if she had been spared. Every follicle on my exposed body dug like claws into me when the dusty wind rustled my hair. Why did the wind sound like bees? I braced for the stings. They never came. I tried to soothe myself by cracking my back, but it was already done. Birds and bees were in the whirling devil around me. I blinked my one eye, having never teared at pain before. My love for my partner welled and drowned me, knowing I'd never see her again. It was a cold reality. So cold I was shivering. I considered this. I thought that the new body was numb, but I was really on ice the whole time? Why wouldn't it just devour me, why did I feel so much pain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my first nightmares progressed, I went to what they call hell. Fleeing the fire, I was on a trail bound for the woods. As I climbed up into the forest, it became night. For the first time, I saw trees, not from underneath, but from the side. Like the shapes who took me, they were dark silhouettes, gnarled things, and they wanted back the bark I'd chewed. They were horrifying. I tried to run faster than the wind, tried to be the wind, but I still saw the trees skin, their hands reaching for me. I had a hard time not dying of fright from the skin hands. They bowed and reached for me, gracing my ears. So these were hands, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winds rushed through the trees as they collected me. Whispering and screeching, they enclosed me and discussed my fate. I didn't want to know their language, but now that I do, I can't forget it. It was very cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They talked about my body and what they would do to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I awoke, I was being hunted by the beast shapes again. I realized they sounded just like the skin trees. They approached, and they whispered and wailed all night by what looked to be the remaining fire. How terrible were these tree beasts, that with their skin, they don't kindle. They must be the source of the fire, I realized. They were going to cook me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cube had soft things for me to lay in. The pain throbbed my whole body. I was so still. If only my mother could see me now. If only I could scratch my ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was moved by the beast. As it lifted me, my down eye peeled off of the softness. Cold water was running over my face. I tried to blink, but I don't think that's what happened. Just like when kicking off, I was infantile in my execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screaming wasn't an option when they put me back down on my bad side. If I was to escape, I'd need them to think I was dead, so I had to stay so quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was that? That thing? I didn't want that. I heard them say &amp;quot;broccoli&amp;quot; when they put it in my personal space. It was like the trees didn't even know how to eat me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were warm, and smelled of their fleshy meals. I knew they had been eating meat, the &amp;quot;broccoli&amp;quot; smelled like the field goliaths. Were these even trees? No, I remember realizing, they're people. My Mother always taught me to stay far away from people, because they were supposed to be the deadliest hunters. But these weren't very lethal, they were stupid for sure. Maybe that really is what people are though, I realized, having never encountered them before. My partner would get breakfast by the people's homes, but I knew to stay where it smelled green. These people smell green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why couldn't I just go home? Someone else would take it soon. This broccoli was so big, how would I chew it? My mouth wouldn't move, I tried to lick a pest off of my nose, but no. It just kept biting. I needed to suckle. I'd been born again to people. People tree beasts, smell like green, and not too bright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, I knew she wasn't going to be saved by rebirth. It had to do with the people beasts that I was reborn. I began to envy her for what must’ve been a swift demise. If they're this bad at killing me, what else will they try? Had they already killed all the others with their firepower? If so, why did I smell trees still? This was a confusing time. The night sky light told me that I'd be this way for a long time. I was shocked that I was going to be at all. Would I feel more and more pain? I licked my paw to keep from screaming. It turned out to be true that I'd never see her again. She was lost to that itchy smoke, that smoke that was ebbing in and out of my nares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd never faced grief in my past life. As a kit, I was a little much for my mother. My two sisters and brother called me Pipsqueak, being the runt and all. They wished they hadn't when by the second week I was as fat as a young buck. That's part of why I was out of the nest so early. Foraging was hard. I scooted about for hours to the first aromatic thing, savored the juices and fibers, and found the next. Life got sweeter with each precious, tender shoot. Some of the best treats were hard-won in the woods across the way from where I stayed. I'd learned to cross, even though I felt exposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met Onawa in those woods. She was older, wiser, and had a big soft belly I loved. I remember dancing for her. She was not very impressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In time, she came to love me, though. I'd see her, and greet her with a good ruffing all the time, until one day she let me mount her. That's when we became partners. I'll never forget her, or the way she let me have her droppings before I went home. Ah, life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these things hit me in waves of profound knowledge. I was the wisest I'd ever been, yet my thoughts kept racing. My head hurt. I flopped myself into a better spot and tried to focus on the misty afternoons in my mind. I felt warm there underneath the soft things. The visions got duller as the pain got sharper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was ICE! Icy ice all around me! I craned to escape. I couldn't. This was no way to die!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the green cube, I couldn’t move my back legs to scratch the stings I could feel. A tick had claimed my earlobe, a fly spat on my eye, and a large dungbeetle lumbered over. When I got a good look at him, I chatted him, asking that he please move out of my personal space. He stuck his butt in the air. It was rude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could smell the earth again. The night had moistened things. We were by a river, I realized. I could smell the fishbones nearby. Ants sampled my body, but mercifully only from the numb parts. Decompositions surrounded me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lying with my collapsed eye upward. I had little experience looking through one of those, but such is par for course when in a new body. There was only a little field of vision left, and what I saw were bats. Many bats spun around my head into the night, picking off of the fruit and broccoli left for me.  I’m not sure the bats ever stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everybody was entitled to what was left of me. This didn’t exclude me necessarily, but the nature of my challenges were that I couldn’t take full advantage. Weak but live, I figured this must be how the beasts want me when they eat. Would I ever be able to fight the fleas again? They really bothered me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning came, and so did soup. It was in a long, hard thing, maybe a bug part? It pumped my mouth full of the strangest food I’d ever tasted, over and over. I ate up gratefully. Since I'd started eating bark, I started to like it all. This soup tasted like the willow bark in back of the cultivated grass. The meal went on and on. Now this really was much better than bark, I tell you! The fleas agreed; their mornings were sweetened as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I smelled no smoke that morning, no evidence of fire. My eyes revealed to me the lush greens and golds I knew before. I couldn’t see much, but I knew that the fire never happened. Bolting to find Onawa would be great, but I was stuck in the clutches of the beasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the beasts was a canine. I felt it scratch at the ground, I heard it whimper. The bigger people beasts wouldn’t let it have me yet. Oh, how long?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside of my cube, my new body shifted and spun. The vibrations made my bones tickle. The tree beasts had us in a firebird, flying across the desert to another land, to their nest? The beasts brought the canine too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many beasts I couldn’t smell spoke and chanted on that ride. My dizzy cube kept speaking to me in muttered music. The breasted beast kept coming in to feed me, not unlike my mother when I was a kit. What exactly they were talking about on that ride, I’m unsure of, but I know it was spring for them too, by the way the did it. The two people beasts were mates. The canine was their kit. Did they know I was now like a kit too? Was it my smell that had them nurturing me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vibrations stopped, they weren’t around, the people beasts. The canine sniffed hungrily at my cube. I had no problem being so still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first arrived in the form I am now, I smelled a feline. I felt reassured, thinking that would surely be the canine’s demise. Felines are so much bigger than canines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The breasted beast continued to fail at eating me. It would come around to give me more of that soup from the bug, the best soup I’d ever had. I noticed that when I was hungry, I hurt so badly. I tried chatting it many times to tell it how much I loved the soup, that I only wanted more and more, but it didn’t matter. It’d give me soup, I’d feel better, then after a while the bats and birds circling over my head returned. For days I’d linger in that form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on the soup when the beast almost drowned me. Nimbly, I kicked in the water. It held my rear end down, so I soiled the water. Survival isn’t always becoming of a gentlebuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wrapped me in softness and fed me more amazing soup. This time, the numbness only hit my body.  I thought of Onawa. If there was no fire, and the tree people were invasive but stupid, then she might still be in her field. She might be about to have my kits, I thought. The beast bound my body. The bondage pulled my fur and stiffened my hips. It hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last straw before I escaped was a good one.  They’d been giving me exotic hay, and hey, I wasn’t about to leave that behind. Numbness was fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wriggled my front end up to the border of my form. Even bound, my back end worked better on the soup. I put my front legs on the edge and pulled with all my might. With one extra belly crunch, I was halfway out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spazzed hard, and rolled out onto a soft surface. It bounced. Was all the land like this between me and Onawa, I wondered? I’d never been in this kind of desert, it was warm and springy. I could do this, I remember thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I moved swiftly to cover those few inches I did. Soft obstacles, like little mountains blocked me from simply heading North. Forging a new trail on this land was hard, but the land wasn’t. I would get going, then roll down the tall softness, to bounce right back were I started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had rolled to the edge of the land. My head was off a cliff, my body still grounded. This was badlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feline stalked my hind in the softness. I writhed to get some purchase, but I began to fall off of the cliff. The feline struck me, pinning me between the soft cliff and it’s claws. It picked me up by the bondage, and took me outside, to examine me under the sky lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Felines were smaller than I’d thought, but still I felt tiny in it’s jaws. My good eye watched the grass fly by beneath me. I couldn’t see above, but I knew the bats were back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was another impact!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feline yowled and ran off. The person beast didn’t strike my shaking body, though. It gently collected me in softness. It really didn’t intend to eat me, I realized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beast placed me in the form. It talked to me. I listened. It knew my name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Ooodin... I love you, Odin. Please rest up now.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chatted it back, I felt the love. We fell asleep like this, and the feline stayed away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my mother was killed, I didn’t understand. Nobody was there to save her from the feline attacking our nest. I didn’t understand why I was born again to this beast. Had she lived, could my mother have saved me from all this change?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onawa would have to raise our family without me. I couldn’t save her from uncertainty. Not before, not now. My beast approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Odin, are you hungry, Bunny Boy?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My eyes blink now. I can see the hay and berries with both of them. Only time will tell when, and if, I may be unbound. I’d love to dance again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Short Stories"></category><category term="Fiction"></category></entry><entry><title>The Honey Mushroom is Larger Than Any Other Single Living Problem</title><link href="http://www.hellender.com/blog/honey-mushroom-largest-problem" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hellender</name></author><id>tag:www.hellender.com,2017-06-15:/blog/honey-mushroom-largest-problem</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This essay was originally written in early 2016, and is now being published for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you may have been concerned with politics or tripping on psilocybins, a distantly related freaky fungus has been trying to dominate the world. Located in Eastern Oregon, the largest organism on Earth …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This essay was originally written in early 2016, and is now being published for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you may have been concerned with politics or tripping on psilocybins, a distantly related freaky fungus has been trying to dominate the world. Located in Eastern Oregon, the largest organism on Earth chills and swells, mostly in Malheur Forest. Though it may seem impossible, the humongous honey mushroom isn’t many individuals of the same kind of fungus, but rather a single gigantic living organism. Larger than a family of blue whales, this massive fungus has spread under ground and bark to pose an ecological challenge for researchers that is bigger still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innocuous looking, with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.opb.org/television/programs/ofg/segment/oregon-humongous-fungus/"&gt;golden caps in autumn&lt;/a&gt; and a mere sheath of white under bark the rest of the year, the honey mushroom has a death grip on the local arbor in the tri-state area. Although it has not yet been discovered in California, run, don’t walk — because there’s good reason to believe that it will grow larger. Since its discovery, the honey fungus in Oregon has been measured to be more than 3.5 miles across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1998, many things were really cool that are now trendy again. The youth of the day were fascinated by icons like smiley faces and alien heads. Always responding to popular interest, the scientists (of that seemingly disproportionately distant day long ago before the world knew we were doomed for sure) worked to prove the existence of extraterrestrial visitors, but failed, instead managing to come up with aerial photographs and DNA samples of 112 ailing trees that revealed the enormous alien-like fungal infection’s growth deep in the typically evergreen forests of the Pacific Northwest. First noted in Washington state, Armillaria ostoyae is notable for surrounding trees as well as causing blight and eventual deforestation. That means it’s worse for forest faires than Hexxus on a hot summer day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armillaria root disease has been known for decades to destroy coniferous forests. The underground network mats around the roots of trees and links up to itself by reaching rhizomorphs, forming a network of hyphae that can slowly suffocate whole forests. Over a period of fifty years, affected trees could die slowly. The visible clues would be the white matting under bark, the signature yellow caps emerging after precipitation in the fall, and the near-silent sounds of decaying flora weeping softly in the breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers lost their collective shits when they discovered that the thousands of acres of fungus were a single mushroom. With such a large fungal body to understand, they studied it longer and harder than a teen with a prono magazne. It took DNA tests searching for homozygous strips of DNA where it would be heterozygous (in different organisms of the same kind, not a term for sexual orientation, SJW’s) to determine if the sampled structures from disparate affected areas in Malheur Forest were from different individual organisms or not, and lo and behold, they weren’t. Cue suspense music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South of the first growth discovered, researchers noted the goliath, yellow fungal colony in Oregon spanning approximately 2,200 acres in the Malheur Forest area. By the new millennium, reports indicated that the growth was composed of a single organism that was &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/strange-but-true-largest-organism-is-fungus/"&gt;possibly greater than 8,650 years old&lt;/a&gt;. Rumors about this large fungus emerged, along with a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://wafflesatnoon.com/debunking-the-worlds-largest-mushroom-photo/"&gt;now infamous hoax photo&lt;/a&gt; depicting an approximately twenty-foot tall mushroom being inspected by onlookers. Despite being a waste of time in what’s obviously a slowly but surely mounting crisis, this big joke is the least of concerns regarding the ravenous honey mushroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists believe that the mostly meter-deep underground network of black, enmeshed fungus emerged from a single deviant spore. Although the evil root-like filaments, or mycelium of the Oregon honey mushroom haven’t been weighed (because accomplishing such a feat is apparently quite tricky), it seems to be the largest living organism found on Earth, followed only by the related colony in the slightly less doomed Mount Adams area of Washington (that colony likes to be called the Witch of the North). Some parts of the honey mushroom plunge ten feet or more underground towards Hell, the place this killer organism must've spawned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;With thousands of acres of forestland in danger, it’s disconcerting that there is not yet a clear solution for the forests of the Pacific Northwest in sight. Are we as a society resigned to let this factor into the ongoing camp horror film we’re seemingly hellbent on facilitating? And more importantly, are we really in any danger from this? Yes and no. Yes, obviously this sinful organism needs to die, but until it does, we can rest in peace, because it won’t ruin any vacations or half-assed armed militia occupations anytime soon. A silver lining can be spotted however, (many if tripping) as although considered unpalatable by some, the honey mushroom is resistant to drought&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.extremescience.com/biggest-living-thing.htm"&gt;as well as edible, and may serve as a sort of manna&lt;/a&gt; in other possible ecological crises in years to come. I read that it’s good with butter and garlic. Bon appetit, because if we don’t start doing something (and for most Americans, that usually means eating) about this fiend, it will end us, or at least one of our most precious oxygen-producing forests.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</content></entry></feed>